export const tq = {
  1: [
    {
      id: 'ti9c',
      question: 'Who led Jesus into the wilderness?',
      answer: 'The Holy Spirit led Jesus into the wilderness.',
    },
  ],
  2: [
    {
      id: 'qzua',
      question: 'How long did the devil tempt Jesus in the wilderness?',
      answer: 'The devil tempted Jesus in the wilderness for 40 days.',
    },
  ],
  3: [
    {
      id: 'jpbn',
      question: 'What did the devil challenge Jesus to do with the stones on the ground?',
      answer: 'The devil told Jesus to turn the stones into bread.',
    },
  ],
  4: [
    {
      id: 'ojkz',
      question: 'What was Jesus’ response to the devil?',
      answer: 'Jesus said that it was written that man shall not live on bread alone.',
    },
  ],
  5: [
    {
      id: 'oi56',
      question: 'What did the devil show to Jesus from a high place?',
      answer: 'The devil showed Jesus all of the kingdoms of the world.',
    },
  ],
  7: [
    {
      id: 't1ax',
      question: 'What did the devil want Jesus to do?',
      answer: 'The devil wanted Jesus to bow down before him.',
    },
  ],
  8: [
    {
      id: 'j69z',
      question: 'What was Jesus’ response to the devil?',
      answer:
        'Jesus said that it was written that you must worship the Lord your God, and you must serve him only.',
    },
  ],
  9: [
    {
      id: 'plz7',
      question:
        'What did the devil tell Jesus to do when he took him to the highest point of the temple?',
      answer: 'He told Jesus to jump down from there.',
    },
  ],
  12: [
    {
      id: 'jttf',
      question: 'What was Jesus’ response to the devil?',
      answer: 'Jesus said that it was written that you must not test the Lord your God.',
    },
  ],
  13: [
    {
      id: 'aupr',
      question: 'What did the devil do after Jesus refused to jump from the temple?',
      answer: 'The devil left Jesus until another time.',
    },
  ],
  17: [
    {
      id: 'wnko',
      question:
        'From which book of the scriptures did Jesus read when he stood up in the synagogue?',
      answer: 'Jesus read from the prophet Isaiah.',
    },
  ],
  21: [
    {
      id: 'r497',
      question: 'What did Jesus say was being fulfilled on that day?',
      answer:
        'Jesus said that the scripture he had just read from Isaiah was being fulfilled that day.',
    },
  ],
  24: [
    {
      id: 'wikq',
      question:
        'What kind of reception did Jesus say a prophet receives in his own country?',
      answer: 'Jesus said that no prophet is accepted in his own country.',
    },
  ],
  26: [
    {
      id: 'pdoq',
      question:
        'In Jesus’ first example to the people in the synagogue, where did God send Elijah to help someone?',
      answer:
        'God sent Elijah to Zarephath, near the city of Sidon, to help a widow woman.',
    },
  ],
  27: [
    {
      id: 'ntoc',
      question:
        'From what country was the person God had Elisha help in Jesus’ second example to the people in the synagogue?',
      answer: 'God had Elisha help Naaman, who was from Syria.',
    },
  ],
  28: [
    {
      id: 'ny7z',
      question:
        'How did the people in the synagogue respond when they heard these examples from Jesus?',
      answer: 'They were filled with rage.',
    },
  ],
  29: [
    {
      id: 'x7xq',
      question: 'How did the people in the synagogue try to kill Jesus?',
      answer: 'They planned to throw him off the cliff on which their town was built.',
    },
  ],
  30: [
    {
      id: 'twbl',
      question: 'How did Jesus avoid being killed by the people from the synagogue?',
      answer: 'Jesus walked right through their midst.',
    },
  ],
  34: [
    {
      id: 'dz1m',
      question:
        'In the synagogue, what did the demon speaking through the man know about Jesus?',
      answer: 'The demon said that he knew Jesus was the Holy One of God.',
    },
  ],
  36: [
    {
      id: 'f7m7',
      question: 'How did the people react after Jesus cast out the demon?',
      answer: 'The people were astonished and kept talking about it with one another.',
    },
  ],
  40: [
    {
      id: 'r8mt',
      question: 'What did Jesus do for the sick who were brought to him?',
      answer: 'Jesus laid his hands on each of them and healed them.',
    },
  ],
  41: [
    {
      id: 'xytr',
      question:
        'What did the demons say as they were cast out, and why did Jesus not let them speak?',
      answer:
        'The demons said that Jesus was the Son of God, and Jesus did not let them speak because they knew he was the Christ.',
    },
  ],
  43: [
    {
      id: 'qj8p',
      question: 'What did Jesus say was the reason he was sent?',
      answer:
        'Jesus said he was sent to preach the gospel about the kingdom of God to many cities.',
    },
  ],
};
